Guide to the Individual manuscripts, publications, and artifacts, 150 AD. - 2014 MS2135
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Gay and lesbian publications and ephemera, 1968-1998; MS2135 Series 5; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series contains published materials concerning gays and lesbians in the Washington, D.C. region. The material dates from 1968-1998. It includes programs from the Capital Pride Festival, Gay and Lesbian Freedom Festival, and Reel Affirmations Film Festival, as well as a directory of gay and lesbian businesses and services.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Loose correspondence related to publishing, magazine articles, and pamphlets, 1968-1978; Series 5 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    These items were purchased along with a large collection of books. The books were all cataloged and these loose items have been placed in this artificial series within MS2135.
    The pamphlets include the following titles:
    "They're Not Going To Push Me Around Anymore" by Dr. Paul R. Johnson
    "Homosexuality and Tangents"
    "About Our Children" a publication from Parents and Friends of Gays, 1978
    "Tangents Newsheets #5"
    There is also loose correspondence from the organization One Incorporated. This organization focused on Eduction, Research, Social Services, and Publishing.
  - Paper on the topic of gay college students, Circa 1970-1979; Series 5 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Sexual Minorities and Employment, 1972; Series 5 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Changes in Gay student rights: National Gay Student Center, 02/1977 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Report on Pennsylvania Council for Sexual Minorties, 1977 March; Series 5 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Gay Men's VD Clinic, Washington, DC, 03/03/1977-03/14/1977 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    One document in this folder explains the responsibilities of the Director and Board of the GMVDC. Another talks about Hepatitis testing and the third document is a Board meeting agenda for March 3, 1977.
  - A Planning Guide for a Same-Sex Holy Union Ceremony (Unitarian Universalist], 1978 June; Series 5 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, 1986-1989 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    Various brochures dealing with the subject of AIDS
  - Metropolitan Committee on AIDS issues, 03/02/1988 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    Testimony by Steve Smith, Chair before the Committee on Human Services
  - Pride and gay and lesbian rights buttons, 1987-1993; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 42, Item 2)
    Gift of Susan Niblette Donahue November 20, 2020 (accession 2020.029)
  - T-shirt National March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights, 1987; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 42, Item 3)
  - T-shirt March on Washington for Lesbian, Gay and Bi Equal Rights and Liberation, 1993; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 42, Item 4)
  - T-shirt March on Washington for Lesbian, Gay and Bi Equal Rights and Liberation, 1993; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 42, Item 5)
  - Getting Wet Tales of Lesbian Seductions anthologized by Carol Allain and Rosamund Elwin, 1992; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Ex-Lover Weird Shit a collection of short fiction, poetry and cartoons by Lesbians and Gay men edited by Debra Riggin Waugh, 1994; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Bad Attitude lesbian erotic fiction Vol 8 Nos. 5-6, Vol. 9 Nos 2-4, Vol. 10 No. 1, 1994; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Girlfriends Vol. 2 issue 2, 1994 March - April; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - On Our Backs Vol. 10 Issues 2-3, 1994 - 1995; MS2135 Series 5 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Reel Affirmations, 1994-1997 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - The Other Pages, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    The collection MS2229 The Other Pages: directories has directories from 1994-2007
  - Lesbian and Gay Freedom Festival, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Capital Pride Festival, 1997-1998 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - On the position on homosexuality in the new draft programme from the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Three flyers related to homosexual civil rights, undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
    1. Gay Liberation Front 2. Militant Labour Forum 3. Gay May Day Tribute
  - Winston Book Club newsletter, undated; Series 5 (Box 34, Folder 6)
- Washingtoniana magazines, journals, and newsletters, 1879-1974; MS2135 Series 6; 0.25 Linear feet
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains magazines that were published in Washington, D.C. The magazines date from 1879- ca. 1974. Many of these appear to be publications of one individual or perhaps a small number of individuals. The topics include religion, washington society, banking, and literature
  In all instances the folder contains only one or at most four issues of a particular journal or magazine.
  - The Analostan Magazine Vol. 1 Nos. 1,2,3, 1890-1891 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Describes itself as "A Liteary Magazine Devoted to American Social and Political Life"
  - The Banking and Mercantile World Vol. 7 No. 6, 11/1905-12/1905 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Chance Music Gallifaufry 10 & 11, 1977; Series 6 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - DC Rape Crisis Center A Reference For Women in D.C., Circa 1980 - 2010; Series 6 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - DC Rape Crisis Center Sexual Assault is Everyone's Problem [brochure], Circa 1980-2010; Series 6 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Directory of Women's Media; Women's Institute for Freedom of the Press, 1989; Series 6 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - The Elf. truth will conquer Vol. 1 Nos. 1-4, 09/1879-12/1879 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Describes itself as an amateur monthly journal. Frank Tenney Chamberlin is listed as the editor, printer, publisher.
  - The Georgetown Voice Vol. 3 no. 4, 1971 April 27; MS2135 Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    Gift of Anita Vultaggio 2021 (Accession 2021.014)
  - Hayworth's Aphorisms A Magazine of To Day, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Published monthly by A.D. Hayworth. Describes itself as "An optimistic journal advocating the bright side of life; absolutely essential attributes to the health, happiness and success of humankind."
  - Hillcrest newsletter, September 2006 - October 2010; Series 6 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    Publication of the Hillcrest Community Civic Association.
  - Hillcrest newsletter, November 2010 - December 2012; Series 6 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - The Junior League of Washington, 1964 October 28-30; MS2135 Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    Gift of the Estate of Josephine R. Shepard November 05, 2020 (accession 2020.027).
    This issue includes an image and mention of Josephine and Mary Shepard.
  - Liberty A magazine of Religious Freedmon Vol. VIII No. I, 1913 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    The publication appears to be the work of the Religious Liberty Association based in Takoma Park, Washington, D.C. The editor is identified as W.W. Prescott and the associate editor as C.M. Snow.
  - May Day newspapers, 1971; MS2135 Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - National Illustrated Magazine Vol. 1 No. 8, 1885 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    Describes itself as "History, Biography, incidents of the War, Public Men and Women of the Day."
  - Off the Wall, 1973 ca.-1974 -- --ca. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Describes itself as "It is a weekly newsletter of the U.C.F./ Peoples Union. Bringing resources and information from the metropolitan Wash, area to the attention of the G.W.U. community."
  - Security's Envoy No. 7 and No. 8, 01/1964-04/1964 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    Published by the Security Storage Company. E.K. Morris, Chairman of the Board; Philip Larner Gore, President and Chief Executive Officer; Laurea J. Renshaw, Editor.
  - Spring Movement, 1971 April 8; MS2135 Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - The Tattler No. 67 and No. 69, 01/01/1921-01/15/1921 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    Describes itself as "A Snappy Journal of Society" Published every friday evening by The Tattler News. Co. Tattler building 1813 7th St. N.W. The editor in chief was Fred R. Byrd.
  - Transition Gallimaufry 8 & 9, undated; Series 6 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Washington News Letter A monthly Magazine Vol XVI No. 8; Vol. XVIL Nos. 10 and 12; Vol. XVIII Nos. 2-3. (5 issues total), 05/1911-12/1912 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    Washington News Letter Unchain the Truth, It Shall Be Free. The issue from Vol XVI No. 8 describes itself as "A Monthly Magazine of Devine Healing" Oliver C. Sabin is listed as the Editor; Paulina B. Sabin as Managing Editor; Oliver C. Sabin, Jr. as Business Manager.
  - The Washingtonian An Illustrated Monthly Magazine Vol. 1 Nos. 1 and 3, 1897 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    Published by the Washingtonian Company. A.D. Hayworth listed as the person who copyrighted it back in 1897.
  - Washington Metropolitan Women's Yellow Pages, 1988; Series 6 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Welcome To Our Schools District of Columbia Public Schools, 1988-1989; Series 6 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Window #2, 1976; Series 6 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - The Woodlothian, 1924 October - 1925 May; Series 6; 9 item(s) 9 newletters (Box 34, Folder 8)
    The Woodlothian was a publication for the employees of the Woodward & Lothrop Department Store. The newsletter contains articles about the history of the store and its founders Samuel Walter Woodward and Alvin Mason Lothrop, official instructions for staff, staff athletic club scores and highlights, writings about employee vacations as well as information about the health of employees. The "Doings of the Store Family" section contains personal data such as notes regarding marriages, births, and vacations for each floor of the store.
    Other Finding Aids
    The Historical Society of Washington DC holds issues of the Woodlothian from 1924-1994.
- Washington associations, clubs, lodges, and societies, 1845-1948; MS2135 Series 7; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series contains programs, handbooks, certificates of incorporation, bylaws, and membership data for civic associations, masonic lodges, and service organizations located within Washington D.C. These materials date from 1845-1948 with the bulk of the material falling between 1845-1912.
  - Almas Temple of Washington, D.C., 1894-1900 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    Described as the Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine.
  - Articles of Association of the Civic Centre of Washington, D.C., 1906 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Journal of proceedings of the semi-annual and annual sessions of the Grand Lodge of the I.O. of G.T. of the District of Columbia, 06/16/1869-11/27/1869 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    Independent Order of the Good Templars
  - Columbia Lodge 10 of Independent Order of Odd Fellows; Order of Mt. Nebo Encampment No. 6, I.O.O.F. and the Ladies Rebekah Degree Relief Association, No. 1, 1847-1948 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    This folder includes nine separate documents. These documents include a constituion, by-laws, a program, proceedings, a directory of business friends (1941-42), and rules of order, dedication of the new I.O.O. F. temple in 1918.
  - K.F.R. Society, 1878-1912 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    From the 41st annual reunion in 1912 "Since its organization in the White House grounds in 1871, the K.F.R. Society of Washington has held a reunion on the third Thursday in January each year. The meaning of the society's initials has never been disclosed to outsiders and none but members are ever present at the reunions." pg. 5 of the reunion program.
  - Kalorama Citizens Association program at annual dinner, 01/15/1966 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Knights Templar handbook and two ribbons, 1897 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    This is the semi-annual edition. I.L. Johnson is identified as the Grand Recorder.
  - Memorial Association of the District of Columbia: certificate of incorporation, 1884 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - By-laws and Rules of Order of New Jerusalem Lodge No. 9, 1845 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Association in the District of Columbia, 1917 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - The Society of American Military Engineers handbook of aims and activities, undated (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Society of Wahsington Fakirs, 1899-1912 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    This folder contains six documents. These are all programs.
  - The United Service Club, 1889 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    This club was composed of current and former members of the military. The document in this folder is a hanbook which includes the certificate of incorporation, bylaws, a list of members both resident and non-resident.
  - Abraham Lisner, 1884-2011; Series 7 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    This folder contains materials related to the Lisner-Louise Dickson-Hurt Home and also the Will for Abraham Lisner.
    Gift of L. Ward Orem, October 19, 2011 (2011.071)
- Middle Eastern maps, photographs, newspapers, 1845-1946; Series 8; 1.5 Linear Feet 2 flat-boxes
  Arranged in no particular order.
  Purchased by Gelman Library, 2007.
  This series contains photographs, maps, documents, and pamphlets. These materials date from 1845-1946. These items were purchased to support the Middle East Institute book collection housed in Special Collections.
  Maps; Iran; Middle East -- Pictorial works; Middle East
  - Umumi Cep Atlasi by Tuccarzade, 1908; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Ottoatlas
    The text of this item is Turkish in arabic script. It is an Ottoman miliary publication. The maps are equatorial and include Europe, Asia and Africa.
    Economics; World politics
  - Photo album of East African women, Circa 1930; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    Description with album "A photo album of 14 beautiful (clothed) women from the African Horn. Not dated or described, but circa 1930"
  - Continental maps in Ottoman script, 1926; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    Four of these maps are in original jackets. The language is Turkish in Ottoman script. Countries covered include Asia, South America, Europe, and North America.
  - Naksi Mufassai Kusarur, Circa 1920; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    Ottoman text of maps of Iran. complete with jacket showing first Shah
  - Ottoman passport [MH 14], 1845; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    This is Arabic script Turkish.
  - Les Races Humaines Menschenrassen, Circa 1946; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    The language is French.
  - Deutsche Kolonien, 1936; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    Language is German.
- Collection of European periodicals dealing with Armenia, 1895-1922; Series 9
  Arranged alphabetically
  Purchased by Gelman Library, 2007
  This series includes newspapers documenting European newspapers writing about Armenia. The material dates from 1896-1922. The languages of the newspapers include French and Italian. These items were purchased to support the Middle East Institute book collection housed in Special Collections.
  - L'Asino, 1915 December 5; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original folder 1)
  - L'Assiette Au Beurre, 1902 February 26, August 16; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual 37, Folder Original Folder 2)
    Issue devoted to Turkish atrocities
  - Giornale Illustrato dei Viaggi, 1915 October 31; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original folder 3)
  - L'Illustrazione Italiana, undated; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original Folder 4)
  - La Domenica Del Corriere, 1909 May 16-23, 1922 October 1-8; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original Folder 5)
  - Le Petit Journal, 1895 November 24, 1909 May 2, 1910 April 3, 1912 October 27; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original Folder 6)
  - Le Petit Parisien, 1896 September 16; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original Folder 7)
  - Le Patriote Illustre, 1896 October 4; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original Folder 8)
  - Le Rire, 1909 May 15; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original Folder 9)
  - La Tribuna Illustrata, 1909 March 21; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original Folder 10)
  - La Tribuna Supplemento, 1985 November 24, December 10, 22; Series 9 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 37, Folder Original Folder 11)
- Lewis Hotel Training School Course materials, 1951-1958; MS2135 Series 11; Huffman, J. Ford; 1 Linear Feet
  In 1920, Clifford M. Lewis opened the Lewis Hotel Training School located at 2301 Pennsylvania Avenue. The Lewis Hotel Training School offered training in Washington D. C., with lessons that focused on the skills and activities associated with specific hotel jobs. The positions range from "silver and glass pantry workers" to "counter man or girl" to "house detective." Each item provides an overview of the positions and the skills needed to successfully do the job. The school also provided a correspondence program advertised in newspapers around the country including Sacramento, Fort Worth, Hartford, and Little Rock. Over time the school expanded to include training programs including Complete Lewis Hotel Training Course, Lewis Cafeteria and Tea Room Course, Lewis Hotel Accountancy Course, and Lewis Cookery Courses.
  Arranged numerically by lesson
  Gift of J. Ford Huffman, 2022 March 03 (Accession 2022.007)
  This series contains 30 lessons produced by the Lewis Hotel Training school. The series has lessons 1-14, 33, 36-50. These were published between 1951-1958
  Huffman, J. Ford
  - Lewis Hotel Training Course Lessons 1-10, 1951-1954; MS2135 Series 11 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Lewis Hotel Training Course Lessons 11-14, 33, 36-37, 1954; MS2135 Series 11 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Lewis Hotel Training Course Lessons 38-43, 1954-1956; MS2135 Series 11 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Lewis Hotel Training Course Lessons 44-50, 1955-1958; MS2135 Series 11 (Box 46, Folder 4)